# **EESHAN PAUL**

175, Jessore road, Dumdum, Kolkata-55, West-Bengal | 91-9903174609 | eeshanatri2904@gmail.com | github | Linkedin | Portfolio

## **SUMMARY**

Recently graduated in Bachelors of Engineering from Jadavpur University(2022-23). I am a highly motivated software engineer
with strong hands on the below mentioned technical skills. I have experience in building real world projects along with some
research works and wide variety of projects starting from machine learning to web development.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Brevids Internship

Software Engineering Internship

June 2022 to August 2022

• In this project, I developed a video summarizer app using **NLP**, **Flask**, **and AWS EC2**. The app creates multiple reels simultaneously, allowing users to customize them. Once generated, users can download and share the reels online. It simplifies video content processing and sharing for an enhanced user experience.

IIT Dhanbad Summer Research Internship

Research Intern

June 2021 to August 2021

Completing a research paper on Compressive strength of soil with various machine learning algorithms.
 Achieved results-(Xgboost-94.44 percent, GradientBoost-94.28 percent, Randomforest-91.8 percent.)

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- C++,Python,HTML,CSS,Javascript
- AWS, Machine Learning, Flask

## **PROJECTS**

#### **Geolocational Data Analysis**

**Machine Learing Project** 

Machine Learning Developer

August 2021 to October 2021

• This project involves exploratory analysis on geolocational data for helping students in Kolkata find suitable places based on income, exercise, and cooking preferences. The project also identifies the best places for restaurants to set up their shops. This analization is done with the help of K-means Clustering. It also utilizes restaurant data for recommendations and visualizes results using Folium maps. (Link)

Spotify Clone Front end project

Frontend Developer

June 2023

• The project is a Spotify clone developed using **HTML**, **CSS**, and **JavaScript**. It offers users the ability to play a selected number of songs from a predefined playlist. The application's user interface closely resembles Spotify's, allowing users to browse the playlist, play, pause, skip tracks, and to keep track on the duration played. The project employs JavaScript to handle audio playback and track selection, while HTML and CSS are used for structuring and styling the user interface. **(Link)** 

My Portfolio Front end project

Frontend Developer

June 2023

• In this project I have used some really cool advanced HTML,CSS and Javascript. Here, I have specified my works and other stuffs with a really cool UI. I hope it will help you a lot in knowing my strong areas. This also serves as a great project for me to prove my command on the above technologies aforementioned. (Link)

#### **EDUCATION**

• Jadavpur University- (8.19/10.0) CGPA (2019-23)

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- 1648 rank in Google Kickstart-22.
- 998 out of 100k+ rank in Codevita.
- Pupil(1315 rating) in Codeforces
- 1760 rating in Leetcode
- 400+ problems solved in leetcode.
- 514 rating at atcoder.
- 300+ problem solved in GeeksforGeeks.
- Runners up in Green Canvas, Megalith-2019, IIT kharagpur.

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English
- Hindi
- Bengali

### **HOBBIES**

Singing